WMD 我们有WMD
WMD. Got that WMD.
你再往那边去点卖
You got to move it on down.
不好看啊
It ain't pretty.
不必好看啊
Doesn't have to be.
只要让他们离开还值得挽救的区域就成
Just needs to pull them from the places  still worth salvaging.
那好
All right,
之前我跟其它班的警官说过… 现在再跟你们说一遍
I told the other shifts... now I'm telling you.
等这周末我开车到那条街时
When I ride my district  at the end of this week...
我希望街角空无一人
I want to see empty corners.
贩药就只能在这里 或去其他两个自由区
They bring it here,  or the other two free zones...
否则你们该怎么收拾就怎么收拾
or you bang them senseless.
该要怎么处理 动手就是
Anything you need to do, you do.
打到他们有人自己撑不到医院急诊室为止
Up to a body that can't walk itself up  out of the emergency room...
我会给你们做后援 明白么?
I'll back up you and your men.  You understand me?
我已向内部调查科申报了周内的行动
Now, I've detailed our I.I.D. representative  to the range for the entire week.
市民的投诉将由Mello警督集中处理
All citizen complaints will  be handled by Lieutenant Mello here.
不惜一切代价
Whatever it takes.
嘿 我又没犯事 我他妈也有权利
Man, I ain't even dirty.  I got rights and shit.
就记着一条 给我闭嘴
Go with the one about staying silent.
在Hamsterdam就不会出这种鸟事
Shit like this don't happen in Hamsterdam.
我站那怎么啦?
I'm up for just standing somewhere?
大爷的 这是在美国!
Fuck y'all. We in America!
去巴尔的摩西区
West Baltimore.
我对天发誓 Herc警官
I swear to God, Officer Herc,
你把我的宝贝儿放了
you unhook Babycakes...
你让我们去哪就去哪 我对天发誓
and my peoples be down where you want us. Swear to God.
要想搞他们 就得给先他们点颜色看看
Fuck with a man's ride, you're gonna get his attention.
宝贝儿?
Babycakes?
喂喂喂 慢着
Yo, yo, yo, hold up!
我擦 丫的等我律师传吧
Motherfuckers gonna hear from my motherfucking lawyer.
你们丫的太过分
This right here is some outrageous shit.
你以为呢?
You think?
擦你 一群装逼的
Fuck y'all, lying motherfuckers!
各位
Gentlemen.
这个 才算是过分
That is outrageous.
这就对了
That's right.
下来吧 宝贝
Come on, sweetheart.
快滚下来
Bust your ass out of there.
这还是马里兰州的地界
It's still Maryland.
假如你们明天不去Hamsterdam干你们那档子事儿...
But if you all don't take that shit down to Hamsterdam tomorrow...
下次就是西维吉尼亚了
next time it's gonna be West Virginia.
看到北斗星头上的那颗没?
That little star right there, across from the Dipper?
那是正北
That's north.
你们肯定想走另一条路
You wanna go the other way.
混蛋
Assholes.
火线重案组 第三季 第6集
the.wire.s03e06
* When you walk through the garden *
* you gotta watch your back *
* well I beg your pardon *
* walk the straight and narrow track *
* if you walk with Jesus *
* he's gonna save your soul *
* you gotta keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* he's got the fire and the fury *
* at his command *
* well you don't have to worry *
* if you hold on to Jesus hand *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* when the thunder rolls *
* just gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* you gotta help me keep the devil *
"我只是混帮会的" - Avon Barksdale
WMD 我有WMD
WMD. Got that WMD.
Landfill 哥们 Landfill
Landfill, got Landfill, yo.
WMD 我有WMD
WMD. Got that WMD.
来瞧瞧看 Landfill
They all here, man. Landfill.
我们在周内就开始楼内装修
We'll start the interior construction within the week.
也就是说 我们得重新考虑预算了
Which means we need to readdress the budget.
再怎么考虑?
Readdress how?
首先一条 现在钢价已经翻了一番
Well, for one, the price of steel has doubled.
如果现在不买还会再涨一番
It'll triple if we don't buy it now.
不是已经买了么?
Ain't the steel bought already?
不 那只是很少一部分
Not the bulk of it, no.
那部分只是建安成本  早就超出最初预算了
Then there are the gutting costs. They exceeded our original expectations.
我说 他在工地应该戴安全帽的
You, know, he needs to wear that hat when he's on site.
规定啊 你知道不
Code, you know.
建安费用涨了 是么?
Gutting costs went up, huh?
那也是你们改出来的
Well, that was due to your modifications.
就是你们说要加那些阁楼
The changes you asked for  in those loft units.
需要申新许可证
Necessitating new permits.
又多一条延期的理由
Which means another delay.
除非我们赶工
Unless we expedite.
趁周末把设计师和他的人带回来
Bring the architect and his people back  in over the weekend
就能在周一前送去审核
and get something to the city on Monday.
喔 那就还要额外付他工钱咯?
Whoa, ain't that part of his original fee?
对 这是计划外的
No, this was unanticipated.
我说这事是你们搞砸的 不是该由你们摆平的么?
Look, y'all fucked up. So y'all supposed  to take the hit, right?
什么意思?
Excuse me?
我说 我的人又不知道什么建安成本
I mean, my man here don't know  shit about no gutting costs.
也不知道什么钢价
He don't know nothing about  no price of no steel.
他在这只是为了能盖几座楼
He just trying to get some shit built.
这背后的问题应该由专人解决
And y'all supposed to have  the expertise behind this.
我只想说
Only what I'm saying is,
看来专人还没到位啊
it seem like the expertise ain't  where it supposed to be.
Barksdale先生 问题是 做生意预算超支是常事
Unfortunately, Mr. Barksdale, cost overruns  are the nature of the business.
我觉得午饭的时候有必要再谈谈这事
And, well, we should discuss this over lunch.
得了吧 我还要去别的地方
Hell no, man, I got elsewhere to be.
而这个叫Marlo的
And this is the Marlo kid.
是刚加入的新人
He's fresh blood for the organization.
Bell把最好的房产交给了他
Bell's given him the best real estate.
那几座高层拆的时候 Barksdale的人已经拿到想要的东西了
The Barksdale people took what they needed  when the Towers came down,
显然
no problem.
Stringer还从未失手
Stringer hasn't missed a step.
他们还在贩毒?
They're still selling drugs?
很多毒品
Lot of drugs.
他没杀人啊
He's not dropping bodies.
没这个必要 他已经占了想要的街
No, he doesn't need to.  He's got all the corners he needs.
那管我屁事?
And I'm supposed to give a shit?
警督 不出两周
Lieutenant, two weeks,
Bell隔离期就满了...
Bell looked insulated...
到时候 他就像银行一样有钱 一样干净了
like he had enough legitimate front  to be able to be just the bank.
Kima查明 他与毒品脱不开干系
What Kima's found out is he's still  directly involved with the drugs.
要不他为什么跟Stanfield的人当面交涉
Otherwise, why the face-to-face  with the Stanfield kid?
他们现在还是天天联系
He's still connected to the day-to-day.
我们要是再多等半年到八个月
We come back six, eight months...
恐怕连找他问话的机会都没有了 破案就更没希望了
you won't even get him in a room  talking drugs, much less handling any.
现在不动手就没机会了 警督
It's now or never, Lieutenant.
Stringer Bell很"安分"
Stringer Bell is quiet.
如果他不再惹事
And if he's quiet,
我才不在乎是不是一年以后回来
I don't give a fuck  if we come back a year from now...
发现他已经成了Baltimore委员什么的
and find out he's  on the Greater Baltimore Committee.
这部门是处理命案的
This unit is about the bodies.
Foerster警长 请致电2462
Major Foerster, call 2462. Major Foerster.
这是什么玩意?
What the fuck is this?
十页关于警察"英雄事迹"的报告
Ten-page report on the heroic police work...
都是关于帮Dozerman警员找回他的配枪的
undertaken to retrieve Officer Dozerman's  service weapon.
送到楼上去 可以让头头们暂时不来烦你
Send that upstairs, keep the bosses  out of your ass for a while.
这全是你写的?
You actually did all this?
是又如何?
Would it matter if I had?
Jay
Jay,
我是凶杀组的警察...
I'm a murder police...
我手头有个双尸案
I got a double on my plate.
我得去调查
I'm gonna work it.
Fayette和Poppleton都不在 搞什么鸡毛?
We ain't got Fayette and Poppleton neither,  what the fuck?
这事我正在办 包括主路的街角
What you mean you working on it, man????
什么叫你正在办?  这街区我们连家店都没开啊
????Why we ain't at least got a shop  set up down the block?
已经开了
We did.
遇到些挫折而已
There was a setback.
把我们的人赶跑了
Ran our boys off.
谁干的?
Who?
- 只是几个呛行的...  - 听好了
- Just some player, man...  - Listen.
我要他亲口说 雇他就是为了看地盘的
Let him tell me. We hired him for muscle.
那孩子叫Marlo
The boy, Marlo.
Marlo 谁你妈叫Marlo? 他是跟谁混的?
Marlo. Who the fuck is Marlo?  He tied to one of the mobs?
一个年轻的 他自己挑大梁
Young boy. Running it on his own, too.
占这里和大道上差不多15个点
Got maybe 15 spots along here  and the avenue.
一个没人撑腰自己单干的
An independent with no fucking support...
把我们最好的地盘抢光了 那咱们在干嘛?
got all the prime real estate  and we doing what exactly?
被小屁孩赶跑了?
Young boy ran us off the corner?
我你妈已经失去理智了 老兄
I'm losing my motherfucking mind, man.
我并非有意冒犯你们女士
And I sincerely mean your girl no disrespect...
但Tosha被杀不是因为她刚好在现场
but Tosha wasn't killed  because she just happened by that mess.
我想我们都晓得 对吧?
I think we all know that, right?
她也是帮派成员
She was a player.
对此我们心知肚明
We know that much.
我们调查发现  有证据证明她曾在那开过枪
Look, we got the science that says  she fired a gun when it all went down.
但枪支我们没有找见
Gun wasn't there for us to find...
但这意味着有人拿走了 对吧?
but that just means somebody  grabbed it up, right?
我想说 你们的姐妹
I mean, your girl,
如果大街上大家起了争执
she definitely had her say...
她总是挺有权威摆平的那个
when everybody else on  that street was talking.
没错吧?
Am I wrong?
我有目击证人说她就在现场
Well, I got witnesses on the scene  that said she was there...
就在一群毒贩中间
right in the middle of a drug robbery.
有个叫Omar的小子也在
Boy by the name of Omar was in on it, too.
谁也没说Tosha是个天使
Nobody saying Tosha was an angel.
没人这么说过
Nobody saying that.
但别人到底怎么说?
But what are they saying?
Tosha的同伙
The crew Tosha was running with maybe
或许并没把杀她凶器给扔掉
they didn't throw the shot that killed her...
但如果他们不早点找我坦白的话...
but, if they don't come to me early  and tell the true story...
我可以保证他们在出头前...
I guarantee they won't  breathe a free breath...
都不会呼吸到自由的空气
until them cicadas come back.
你们都知道该对应该的人说什么了
You all get the word to the right people.
你已经和验尸员谈过了 对吧?
And you've spoken to the medical examiner,  correct?
他怎么说?
What's he say?
他说有些起伏不定
He says it's lumpy.
起伏?
Lumpy?
他说如果调查可以提出一个可靠的情境的话...
He says that if an investigation  can come up with a credible scenario...
他愿意将死因改成凶杀
he's willing to change the cause  of death to homicide.
那你找到嫌犯了么?
Do you even have a suspect here?
呃... 没
No.
听着 我不知道你们那边怎么做...
Look, I don't know how you city guys do it...
但在Annapolis市 我们要避开一两个风头
but down here in Annapolis we try  to duck a punch or two.
不是往每个风口浪尖上去撞
Not lean into every last one.
我的县不能再出命案了
My county doesn't need another murder.
女士们 Wright牧师 来认识一下我丈夫Cedric Daniels
Ladies, Reverend Wright, I'd like you  to meet my husband Cedric Daniels.
幸会
Nice to meet you.
我不是说我看到了什么 没有
Not that I've seen, no.
没人邀请她吧 嗯?
She was invited, right?
当然 Eunetta最近都没管什么事了
Oh, of course. Eunetta doesn't make it  too much nowadays.
在议会那边也是一样
Not even Council meetings.
估计Eunetta已经全身心投入初选了
I think Eunetta's gonna have her hands full,  come the primary.
市长会保她过关的
Mayor will pull her through.
他还是大权在握么?
He still have coattails?
废话
Shit, boy.
你去翻字典查查"现任"
You look up "incumbent"  in the damn dictionary...
你就会看到Clarence Royce在朝你微笑
and you'll see Clarence Royce  smiling back at you.
他可是一往无前的
He gets his whole ticket through.
新的市长民意调查
The Mayor's got a new poll  showing his negatives
已经说明去年一年 他的负面印象直线上升
have really jumped in the last year.
他可没打算办记者会把一切公之于众啊
Not that he's gonna be putting a press  release out about that.
听说你那天因为目击证人被杀 当着他的面发飙了啊
I hear you took a swipe at His Honor  the other day on that witness murder.
那并不是对市长的
Well, not at the Mayor directly.
但我们警察在小组委员会面前颜面无存啊
But we had the police brass  in front of the subcommittee and,
我也不知道
I don't know,
发生这种事情是不可原谅的
there's just no excuse for what happened.
继续坚持吧 议员们
You keep on it, Councilman.
眼下的一点挫折对委员会是件天大的好事
A little smack here and there  does this administration a world of good.
这就是议会需要新鲜血液的原因
That's why we need new blood on the Council.
好让人人都诚实可靠
Keep everybody honest.
多好啊
Yeah.
别自取其辱了
Don't embarrass yourself.
我说
So.
你那命案根本没法按照谋杀案调查了
Your murder's never gonna be a murder...
Daniels根本完全在顾另一桩案子
and Daniels' got his head all up  in another case.
我知道
I know.
你也知道做警察最难的是什么
You know what the hardest part  about being a police is?
知道 就是得跟妻子解释
Yeah. Explaining to your wife
为什么你的肾感染 而她要服抗生素
why she has to take antibiotics  for your kidney infection.
我是想说最难的是把这份工作当真
I was gonna say trying to make the job  actually matter.
这也算
That, too.
说到你前妻
Speaking of your ex-wife,
- 到底怎么了? - 没什么
- what's up there?  - Nothing.
她跟个律师好上了
She got her hooks in some lawyer.
有钱的主
Money guy.
我操 操那贱人
Fuck it and fuck her.
那又怎样 你现在放得下了么?
So what, you moving on?
当然 既然你问到 我现在又重燃希望了
Yeah, I might have some fresh hope,  now that you mention it.
是么?
Yeah?
有位女士 为我孩子做着点事
Yeah, there was this woman  at this thing for my kids.
她好像 在为学校筹款什么的
She, like, raises money for the school  and all that, you know?
人漂亮又机灵 全都赶上了
She's got a face, a body,  and a brain all working together.
她就好像是那种
And she looks like the kind
会在我不堪的时候 提醒我的人我正需要这样的人
who might tell me when my shit stinks  which is probably what I need.
她就跟女版Freamon一样
She's kind of like Freamon with tits.
那你有她电话了吗?
So what, you get her number?
没 还没有
No, not exactly.
嘿 如果我连一个巴尔的摩的女性白人 都找不到
Hey, what kind of detective would I be...
我还算个什么警员 对不?
if I couldn't track a white woman  in Baltimore, right?
加油吧
There you go.
看她要点什么
See what she wants, okay?
今晚你很灵光啊
You were so smooth tonight.
你几乎让他们照单全收了啊
You had them eating right out of your hand.
这不正是你期待的么?
It's what you need from me, right?
总之还算凑合
Anyway, it wasn't too bad.
我猜 我是锻炼出来了吧
I'm getting better at it, I guess.
真的是呢
You are.
Cedric 或许我们该...
Cedric, maybe we could...
我也不知道
I don't know.
现在
Right now,
告诉我该站在哪队...
you tell me where you need me...
不管你想我是在A还是B队 我都会去
and whether you want the Class A  or the Class B uniform, and I'm there.
除此以外的 我就不知道了
More than that, I just don't know.
然后呢?
So?
然后什么?
我问你呢 搞什么?
I'm saying, what the fuck?
先深呼吸下 哥们
Take a deep breath, man.
我是说 深呼吸下
I mean, take a long deep breath.
如果你能发话 我们就开干
Know that if you call the shot, we at war.
即便开打 我还是会陪你
We at war.I'm there like I always been.
要知道 那地界已经今非昔比了
Thing about turf, man, it ain't like it was.
我是说 你没必要为多几个街角破费
I mean, you ain't gotta pay no price  of buying no corners.
我们要街角什么时候开始花钱了?
Since when do we buy corners?
我们要直接占
We take corners.
我说 不管怎么样 说到底还是要靠钱
Man, you gonna buy one way or another.
我们不是要毁尸灭迹
Whether it's with the bodies we done lost
就是要前前后后为那些毒品打点操劳
or you're gonna lose time in the joint  that's behind us or ahead of us...
我是说 玩这个必须得有投入
I mean, you gonna get some shit  in this game,
天下没有免费的午餐
but it ain't shit for free.
我说 我们到底需要多少个街角?
I mean, how many corners do we need?
我们一个人能挣多少?
How much money can a nigga make?
比要花的多
More than a nigga can spend.
那样的话  我们就不能在这里花我们已经赚到的钱了
And then we ain't gonna be around  to spend what we done made already.
妈的 谁想我会在这呆这么久
Shit, I didn't think I was gonna  be around this long.
是啊 但事已至此了
Yeah. Well, we here now.
事实上我们城里其它帮派 无论东区 还是西区的
The fact is we got every mob in town,  East Side, West Side...
已经准备合作了
ready to pull together,
拿到的都是Prop Joe给的好货 共享地盘
share territory on that good shit  that Prop Joe putting out there.
咱们在闹市区出货 有票子赚
We take that shit downtown  and we get in the money game
也没有黑鬼会进局子了
and that niggas ain't going to jail.
我说 咱们已经过了打打杀杀时候了
I mean, we past that run-and-gun shit, man...
况且 我们已经给自己找了能赚大钱的活
like, we find us a package and we ain't  got to see nothing but bank.
就是给钱赚 与街角无关 与地盘也没关系 毫无关联
Nothing but cash. No corners,  no territory, nothing.
我们赚了那么多合法的钱 老兄
We make so much goddamn straight money, man...
即便政府来调查我们
the government come after us, man,
他们屁也不能放一个
ain't shit they can say.
生意人对吧?
Businessmen, huh?
让年轻人为销售操心去
Let the young'uns worry about how to retail...
我们只管批发
where to wholesale.
我说 谁管你街角站的是谁
I mean, who gives a fuck who's standing  on what corner...
如果我们从源头开始...
if we're taking that shit off the top...
好好利用这些优势
putting that shit to good use,
让那玩意为咱们卖命
making that shit work for us.
由我们控制的就不止是街角了 B
We can run more than corners, B.
就是这样
Period.
咱们就像小Willie
We could do like Little Willie, man...
像他过去那么有钱
back in the day, with all that number money...
经营整座该死的城市
and run this goddamn city.
像商人一样
Like businessmen.
让我先跟那个叫Marlo的小子谈谈
Man, just let me talk to the boy, Marlo.
看能不能把这事摆平
See if I can't smooth this shit out.
要我说这事不可能一蹴而就 因为那黑鬼就是一根筋
I mean, it ain't gonna be overnight 'cause  the nigga only knows what he knows.
但我应该能让他明白过来
But I think I could talk some sense  in his head.
我不像你能习惯西装革履
Yeah, I ain't no suit-wearing businessman  like you.
我只是个混帮会的
You know, I'm just a gangster, I suppose.
我就是想要我的街角
And I want my corners.
电视播的是HBO的经典剧OZ 是同志情人的对话
跟你说
I gotta tell you,
自从你被保释 我就一直魂不守舍
I'm having a tough time wrapping my head  around the reality of you being paroled.
相信我 第一杯马爹利下肚前 我就是无法理解
Trust me, I won't fully comprehend it  until I'm sipping my first martini.
Toby 我...
Toby, I'm...
凶杀组警察去找Tosha的人了
Homicide police went to Tosha people.
他们说知道这里有她的事
Talking about how they know  she was in the mix.
他们说有目击证人 还提到了你的名字
Saying they got witnesses and shit.  They called your name on it, too.
- 他们说什么了?  - 他们联系我的
- So what they say?  - They called me.
等等 我认识这个条子
Hey, yo, I know this cop, man.
是嘛? 那是不是该顺着他
Yeah? Maybe we should help him out.
告诉他是谁干的 又干了什么
Tell him who did what.
冷静点 Kimmy
Man, stop wilding, Kimmy.
得了 这事我知道了
All right, now I said I got this.
Tosha的人让我告诉她们 那天到底出了什么事
Tosha's people want to know from me exactly  what happened that day.
我只能说这个啊
That's all I'm saying.
跟他们说 她撞见个想杀那几个小子的人
Well, tell them she caught one trying  to take them boys down, man.
没必要把警察扯进来
Ain't no need to involve the police  in none of this.
我看 那警察已经盯上这事儿了
Sound to me like he involved already.
跟你说Kimmy 这事我来搞定
Kimmy, I told you, I got this.
我丈夫是为美国罐头公司的Cooper先生工作
My husband worked for Mr. Cooper  at the American Can.
他的收入不少
He made good money.
我们攒钱买下了这栋房子
We saved up and bought this house.
这旁边还住着几家白人呢
There were some white families still  living in the neighborhood then.
邻里是改变不少 Hazel太太
The neighborhood has changed, Mrs. Hazel.
这是那房子的照片
This is a picture of the house.
噢
Oh.
市政府的房源 税也缴了
City-owned, taxes paid and all.
真是不错
It is very nice.
但恐怕我负担不起
But I can't afford that.
别为钱的事担心
You don't have to worry about the money.
已经都解决了
It's all taken care of.
这是我们的一项特殊计划
It's a special program we have.
是为了
It's for ...
是为了居住环境...
It's for people who are living in
很糟糕的人 就比如...
really bad situations you know,
像你门口这样有毒贩的情况
with the drug trafficking you see outside.
这里住的人都很好
And this is a good neighborhood.
很安全 就在19路沿线上
It's safe and it's on the number 19 line.
而且步行就能到你的教会
And it's walking distance from your church.
警官
Officer,
这里是我唯一的家
this is the only home I know.
这是我的全部
It's all I've got.
这会你说有项计划
Now, you say you have a program
可以把我安排到别的地方去
that can place me somewhere else.
但你对我家门外的就没个计划么?
But you ain't got no program  for what's outside my door?
你没说谎
You weren't lying.
告诉过你的
Yeah, I told you.
按你说的我已经绕遍这些街区
And I've been all over these blocks  like you said.
没见有摄像头 也没人监视
I haven't seen any cameras, nobody peeking.
秃头佬和他的人已经在这边盯了好几天了
And Monk Man and his crew been here  for grinding for days...
毒贩子们都毫无避讳啊
and narcos ain't even blink.
你听好了
I'll tell you what.
安排几个我的人去 别太多 年轻的就行
Put some of my people on it.  Not too many. Just them young'uns.
货量少点 防止这里搞陷阱
Make the package real small,  just in case this a trap.
这事你直接跟我报备
I wanna hear directly from you on this.
交给我了
I'm on it.
多他妈让人搞不清楚状况啊
This shit is just bugged out, you know?
String打电话过来说 他有点事要晚会到
String called, said to tell you  he gonna be late.
是你说我们不行 对吧?
So, what you telling me, we weak?
老大 我跟Black Donnie已经说过了
Boss, I reached out to Black Donnie.
有什么就说 你听着 少他妈跟我扯淡
Okay, spit it out, man. Listen,  stop fucking double-talking me.
Black Donnie说他才不买账
Black Donnie say he ain't having any of it.
他说Mouzone兄弟把咱们骂得狗血喷头
Say Brother Mouzone put a hex on all of us.
那Peacock呢?
What about Peacock?
Peacock去雇了几个多米尼加人
Peacock went and hired out  with some Dominicans.
Eggy Mule呢?
What about Eggy Mule?
Eggy进去了 联邦调查局的因为一把枪把他关了
Eggy locked up. Caught a nickel  with the Feds for a pistol.
Shorty Boyd什么情况?
What about Shorty Boyd?
Shorty Boyd走了 已经洗手不干了
Shorty Boyd went and cleaned his whole act up.
知道么 把我们全耍了
Yeah, I know. Fucked us all up.
那我们现在怎么办?
What we got?
就你给我们的那个叫Cutty的大兵没问题
The soldier you sent at us, Cutty,  he gonna work out...
但其它那几位 我就说不好了
but the rest of them dudes, I don't know.
那你听好了 大块头
All right, listen, big man,
一会你就能轻松挣你他妈的大钱了
you about to earn your fucking  keep around here, right now.
等会出去找Cutty
You go out, you get Cutty
在几个身手好的 把Marlo给我废了
and get the best of the rest  and you put a hurting on Marlo.
我要夺回我的街角
I want my corners.
搞什么?
What the fuck?
这是干嘛?
What now?
出问题了 Bell先生
Problems, Mr. Bell.
现在不是时候啊 我要去赴约了
No, this ain't the time for problems, man.  I got places to be.
我们已经接到通知说
We're being told it may take weeks before
在城市巡查回来签署调整前可能要拖几周
we get the city inspectors back down here  to approve these site changes.
几周?
Weeks?
我们等越久 你的损失就越大
Every day we wait, you lose money.
搞什么? 这样搞 干这行的怎么可能赚钱啊?
Man, what the fuck? How does anybody  make any money in this game, man?
每次我以为说定了的 结果我又要多掏钱
Every time I think we good,  you back in my pockets.
- 你得打个电话 - 又来?
- You need to make a call.  - Again?
那人是你的顾问 对吧
He's the consultant, right?
那个人是你花不少钱请的顾问 是吧
You're paying him a nice chunk  of change to consult, right?
这就是为什么要雇个跟政客有关联的人
This is why we have a politically-connected  guy like that on the payroll.
他要去市里办我们自己没法办的事情
He goes downtown and does for us  what we can't do for ourselves.
民主要行动了啊 Bell先生
Democracy in action, Mr. Bell.
好了 听我说
All right, look.
我跟Slim会设法穿过小道 从侧面进攻
Me and Slim, we're gonna work through  the alleys and hit them from the side.
而你要从这过来
I want you to come through here.
慢慢地开过路口
Slow down, through the intersection.
喔
Oh.
为啥我们不直接从这条路上过?
Why don't we just come up this way?
这就不用担心通过什么路口了
Then we ain't got to worry  about crossing no intersection.
这条路?
Come that way?
你就等于把司机搁在枪口前了
You putting your driver  in the line of fire, man.
过脑子想想
Think on it.
他会干掉
He getting taken out.
车就没了
Car gonna crash.
到时候你坐什么去?
Now, where that put you at?
再者说 你不想隔着自己的司机开枪吧?
Besides you don't wanna be shooting  across your driver, do you?
那好 下面的就容易了
All right, so come in easy.
他们不会发现你
They ain't gonna be looking for you
因为这些人的注意力都在我们这
'cause we gonna have they full attention.
然后 看准了目标
And, look, pick your targets,
干掉以后尽快离开
drop them and move out quick.
- 谁开车? - 我负责开车
- Who driving?  - I'm under the wheel.
你要想办法在出街区前减速...
All right, you make sure you slow down  at the end of the block...
然后把武器扔了
and toss your weapons.
还要把车里的所有弹壳拣出来
And get rid of any shell casings  that kick back in the car.
要不警察会追查到得
Police can trace them shits.
手套也得扔 对吧
Toss the gloves, too, right?
不是 手套要留着
No, hold on to them.
他们能从上面提取完整的DNA
They're gonna have that DNA shit  all on them.
那好 我们布置好还要点时间...
All right, look, it's gonna  take us some time to get set up...
所以就要你们在4到5个街区外等着
so we need y'all to lay back  about four or five blocks.
等准备好了  就电话通知你们
And when we ready, we're gonna hit you  on the burner...
但各位务必要守到我拨电话 明白么?
but y'all hold tight till I call you.  You got it?
我们的事自然会处理
We gonna handle our end.
可你们得保证别在那留个尾巴坑我们...
You just make sure there's some fucking work  left out there for us...
我可不想被别人瓮中捉鳖了
'cause I don't wanna feel  like I'm just some damn decoy.
说的就是
Damn right about that.
只是搬迁一下 没什么大不了的
It's just to relocate, no big deal.
又不是请求24小时保护什么的
I'm not asking for round-the-clock  protection or anything like that.
没什么大不了?
No big deal?
我说Bunny啊 我去哪给这老太太找房子?
Come on, Bunny where the fuck am I  gonna find a house for this old broad?
我已经找好了
I got one already.
Harford路有一处接管的
It's a foreclosure up on the Harford Road.
您需要做的只是批了这份紧急申请 我的人就能帮她搬进去
All you gotta do is file the emergency  petition my boys'll move her in.
而且她是行凶毒贩的目击证人
And she's witnessing  against a violent drug crew.
要是没她合作 恐怕就不会取得进展
Without her cooperation,  I doubt if it'll go forward.
她都已经73了
She's 73 years old.
这么大年纪还这么英勇 我就怕...
Brave old broad to be doing this,  I guess, but...
签吧 Ray
Come on, Ray.
我们才少了一个毒品案件的目击证人
Look, we just lost a witness in a drug case.
你肯定不想这么快再少一个吧
We don't wanna lose another one so quick.
要是Rawls知道了 可是你逼着我签的
If Rawls gets wind of this,  you forged my signature.
那她现在住哪?
Where is she living now, anyway?
Vincent街 第二区
She's on Vincent Street, Sector Two.
那可不是什么好地方吧
It's a bad location, huh?
说了你也不会信的
You wouldn't believe it.
我们应该在这等电话
We should wait for the call.
要是他们有人盯梢呢?
Man, what if that crew got lookouts?
要是我们傻等 到时候过去就什么都完了
Motherfucker, if we wait,  it'll be all over time we get there.
再说了 你看 我是说
Man, plus, look, man, I'm saying
到时候怎么跟Avon混?
how's that gonna play with Avon, man?
好处都他们拿去了
They taking all the credit.
哥几个 抄家伙
Yo, fellas, strap up.
那边不是他妈Nay-Nay么
There go that motherfucker Nay-Nay, man.
咱们过去干了他
I say we take him.
我们应该在这等电话
We should wait for the call.
等什么 一会他就跑了
Man, we wait, he gonna get away, man.
上 上 上
Go, go, go!
出去 出去
Get out, get out!
搞什么鬼?
What the fuck?
刚刚不是说了等我电话么?
Didn't I say something about  waiting for a fucking phone call?
请你去露脸儿的邀请 你怎么一半都拒掉了
You know how you blow off half the  invitations you get to be somewhere?
去剪彩 来之前要操场清场之类的屁事儿
Ribbon cuttings, playground clean-ups  and shit?
没办法 我别无选择
I got to. No choice.
我那天是要剪个彩的
I was gonna cut out on one the other day.
知道么? 我为Delta Phis筹集资金
It was a fundraiser for the Delta Phis,  you know?
但懒人我倒是去了研讨会那边表示支持来着
But I drag-ass over  to the Forum to show the flag.
只有老Odell Watkins在那大放厥词
And who was there in his ironsides  but old Odell Watkins.
游说成性的家伙
The rainmaker himself.
当别人面一直说市长让他怎么怎么失望
Yeah, talking in public about being kind  of disappointed in the Mayor.
失望 真的?
Disappointed. Yeah?
怎么失望了?
Like how?
相当的失望
Like sincerely disappointed.
就像是对自己小孩一样
The way you'd be with one of your kids.
就像是他想看市长的难堪
Like he really wanted  to see the Mayor pressed, you know?
我就想了
Got me thinking.
没准明年初选有人能跟Royce对抗
Maybe somebody can take a run  at Royce in next year's primary.
哪根葱啊
Like who?
女议会主席?
Madam Council President?
Mickey Pepper会跟他拼的
Well, Mickey Pepper would give him a fight.
不会 Mick说过他不想离开法政圈子
No, Mick's already said he doesn't  want to leave the legislature.
他才不会冒这险
He won't risk it.
你得找些有种的人
Well, you gotta have someone with balls.
而且是黑人
And somebody black.
这里可是巴尔的摩
This being Baltimore and all.
你们拿了几个?
How many y'all take?
两个
Two.
一轮都没打光啊
Didn't get nearly a shot off.
Barksdale那些人真没本事
Speak to the quality of Barksdale people.
他会回来找你的
He's gonna have to come back at you.
你知道不会就这么了事的
You know it ain't gonna stop at this.
我没想要结束
I don't want it to stop.
Barksdale今天也不怎么样
Barksdale weak today.
他没用我给的弹药
And he ain't working  with the ammunition I got.
那是肯定的啊 你拿的可是满弹夹的
No doubt, you carrying a full clip.
但要是换你 事到临头了会怎样?
But what you gonna do when you sitting  at the head of the table?
要是你在那
Once you there,
你就得忍为上
you got to hold it down.
听上去他们当中有人麻烦大了
Sound like one of them good problems.
是啊
Yeah.
不论监狱还是墓地...
Prison and graveyards...
全是喜欢出头的年轻人
full of boys who wore the crown.
关键是他们能出头
Point is, they wore it.
现在该到我了
It's my turn to wear it now.
咱们一起干吧 Chris
We're gonna do this, right, Chris?
- 一起干吧 小子 - 我昨天就准备好了 兄弟
- Gonna do this, son - . It's ready like yesterday, dawg.
要白T恤么 老兄?
Want a white T's, man?
要给自己找件白T恤么
Need to get yourself a white T, dawg.
开始实施你的计划了 Bubs?
So you working your plan, huh, Bubs?
这赚点 那赚点嘛 Kima
Dollar here, dollar there, Kima.
怎么了 为什么打电话给我
So, what's up? Why you call?
那只是报个道
Was just checking in.
你们还是对那个叫Marlo的感兴趣 对吧?
You're still interested in that boy,  Marlo, right?
没兴趣?
No?
你要真想多赚钱  就该直接去公园高地那边...
You wanna keep getting paid, you need  to get your ass up to Park Heights...
学学那个叫Kintel牙买加人占个街角
school yourself on that Jamaican  named Kintel got them corners.
Kintel?
Kintel, huh?
我们老大完全不鸟Marlo的事
My bosses don't give a fuck about Marlo.
Stringer的人也一样
Stringer's people neither.
真惨
That's too bad.
说的是
Yeah.
因为我们这又出事了
'Cause now we got a whole lot of drama.
怎么了?
What happened?
Marlo那小子开始占地为王了
That young buck, Marlo,  ain't getting runned off.
他刚在Mount和Fayette 那干掉两个Barksdale的人
He just dropped two of Barksdale soldiers  on the corner of Mount and Fayette.
- 就两个小时前 - 什么?
- Two hours past.  - What?
在街那边一场恶战
Corners is all jumping bad.
我以为是Stringer让Marlo占的街 我看到他们碰头了
I thought Marlo had them corners  for Stringer. We saw them meet.
不知道你看到了什么
I don't know what you saw.
我只知道Marlo翅膀已经硬了
All I know is Marlo  is flying his own colors.
西区已经快成巴格达了
West Side's about to be all Baghdad  and shit.
但是你们都在找Jake 什么名字来着  Kintel?
But y'all looking for Jake,  what's his name? Kintel?
我说你们太没把Bubs当回事儿了吧 我发誓
Y'all are too fickle with Bubs, man.  I swear.
一点小意思 给你们的
A little gift for you and your boys.
有空打电话
Call me.
白T恤 白T恤
Whitey sale! Whitey sale!
副局 我知道那事 我的手下正在调查
Deputy, I am aware of the incident  and my men are on it.
我们已经安排了防爆警察值班 DEU组的人已经开始地毯式搜查了
We called in the 7-to-3 flex squad early  and my DEU is out canvassing.
情况掌握到什么程度?
And what do we know?
似乎只能是帮派火并  凶杀组那边有什么进展?
Only that it seems to be rival gangs.  But, what does homicide have?
去他的凶杀组
Fuck homicide.
警长 我现在问的是你
I'm asking you for answers right now, Major.
- 长官 我的人... - 可你显然是一无所获
- Sir, my men...  - And you damn sure have none.
我的人正在...
My men are out there...
我们现在掌握什么可以汇报给老大的?
What do we know that we can actually  tell the man?
就像你刚说的 帮派火并
It's like you said. Rival gangs.
不 是那些帮派?
No, which gangs?
帮派呗 那群混蛋看谁都不顺眼
Gangs. Assholes who don't like each other.
抱歉 警长 我们现在确实没有进展
I'm sorry, Major, but we got nothing on it.
出啊 怎么打都无所谓
Play it. It don't make me no never mind.
全靠大牌
It's all about trumps.
晚上好阿 Omar
Evening, Omar.
晚上好 Bruiser
Evening, Bruiser.
现在来说说看王牌吧
Speaking of them trumps now.
嘿 各位
Hey, everybody.
晚上吃什么 Jen? 我饿坏了
What's for dinner, Jen? I'm starving.
在做了
It's working.
嗨 爹地
Hi, Daddy.
过得好么 宝贝
How you doing, beautiful?
爹地 我们一起吃
Daddy, we shared with you.
好啊
That's nice.
Jen 你注意到昨晚我看的那盘带子了么?
Hey, Jen, you seen that tape  I was watching last night?
不知道你说的是哪个
I don't know what you're talking about.
你也来看看
You gotta see this.
那是上周一晚议会的录像
Videotape from last Monday night's  Council meeting.
Keifer想毁灭我的决心 但他那是白费力气
Keiffer tried to block my resolution,  but I laid him out good.
我可是少有的强大啊
I was in rare form, baby.
你见到过那带子么?
You seen that tape?
是不是在录像机里没拿出来?
Maybe you left it in the VCR?
嗯? 我靠
What? Son of a bitch!
- 是谁他妈... - 爹地 Franky要把三明治留给你
- Who the hell...  - Daddy, Franky shared his sandwich with you.
我们把它藏起来了 你到家之前就没人会吃掉咯
We hid it so no one else could eat it  before you came home.
能再给我点薯条和盐黄瓜么?
Can I get some chips and pickles  with that, too?
无意冒犯你
I don't want to disrespect you.
但String对我一直不错
String been good to me, you know?
不光是为我付账
Not just my bills.
Avon和他似乎觉得对我有所亏欠
Him and Avon probably think  they owe me that much.
并不像别人想象或谈论的那样
And it ain't what people might  be thinking or saying, either.
亲爱的 他们怎么说?
What they saying, honey?
不是说我不想D
It ain't like I don't miss D.
我想的
I do.
是啊  我也想他
Yeah, well, I miss him, too.
可他已经过世有段时间咯
But he's been gone a while now.
一年多了
More than a year.
Stringer人不错
Stringer's fine.
我没否认
No denying that.
在他身边我有安全感
I feel safe around him.
你要是问我 是不是你能跟String在一起...
You asking to get with String...
我没问题
I'm okay with that.
还以为你会生气
Thought you was gonna be mad.
D的事情简直一团糟 知道么?
I mean, everything with D is  so messed up, you know?
每次我一想到这些都会这么觉得
I mean, every time I think about it...
有个警察
And you know this one police...
他一来 就让我的心又乱了
he came by here and brought it all up again.
谁啊?
Who did?
城里来的探员阿
Police detective from the city.
就是那个在D关在泽西的时候 想让他背叛Avon的家伙
The one tried to turn D on Avon  when he got pulled up in Jersey.
那个白人?
White boy?
- 短发的?  - 对
- Bushy hair?  - Yeah.
他说什么了?
What'd he say?
他说
He said...
D'Angelo可能没...
maybe D'Angelo didn't take...
你知道的
You know.
没自杀
Take his own life.
他说这里另有文章
He said maybe it was something else.
他来就是跟你说这个?
And he came to you with that?
有天来这留了张名片
Left his card here one day...
但我什么都没跟他说
but I didn't say nothing to the man.
只跟Stringer说了这事
Just told Stringer, is all.
她要参加议会竞选?
She's gonna run for Council?
是的
She is.
从我的了解 她很可能获胜
Probably win, too, if I know her.
而你是她骄傲的丈夫?
And you're the proud husband?
我都不知道我是个什么感觉了
Not sure how that makes me feel.
那是到明年竞选前做给外人看的
It's just for show  until the election next year.
有个警督站在她身边看着顺眼
A city police lieutenant looks good  on her arm.
谁还在乎这?
Who even cares anymore?
这个国家有一般人都分居
Half the country are separated.
剩下一半正准备再办个离婚咧
The other half are getting divorced  for the second time.
这只是在帮她
This is a favor. For her.
这种事情很难解释的
It's hard to explain.
听着 我之前让她失望过
Look, I disappointed her.
她以前也忍受了我好几年
She lived through me for a lot of years...
跟她说我最次我也会做到副专员...
telling herself I was tracked  for Deputy Commissioner at worst...
不会一直呆在警察局 谁知道呢?
and past the police department, who knows?
很久以前我在东区的时候发生过些事
And there were some things that happened  a long time ago when I was in Eastern.
想来她是想让我更进一步
I guess she wanted more out of me.
之后这么多年 这么多筹划
And after a lot of years and a lot of plans...
结果我还是更适合在警署里领衔
it turns out I have a better head  for police work...
而不是去走仕途
than I do for climbing the ladder.
她还在继续坚持
She hung in there thinking my career
觉得我的人生早晚要出人头地
was going to turn into some kind of big deal.
我可能也给了她错觉 觉得我喜欢平和
And I probably let her believe it  just to keep peace.
现在她想要自己飞黄腾达了
Now she wants to be the big deal.
那你想要什么?
What do you want?
我只是不想让她再失望
I just don't want to disappoint her anymore.
现在...
And right now...
现在我只要戴着戒指穿着警服出现在晚宴上
I'm more help showing up  at some chicken dinner...
对她就是最大的支持
in my wedding ring and dress blues...
这要比没离婚
than being the not-even-divorced-yet husband...
挽着一个白种女人好多了
with the white woman on his arm.
这次我会尽我所能的支持她的理想
I'm going to do what I can to see  she gets what she wants this time around.
再没别的了
Nothing more than that.
最后一次见Gerard 他正在Fayette街枪战
Last seen Gerard, man, he was racing bullets  up on Fayette Street.
他似乎是赢了
He appeared to be winning, too.
听着 在他重新出现之前
Look, man, till he shows back up here...
那发生的事我们也不得而知
we ain't gonna know what happened out there.
有件事情我他妈是很确定的
I damn sure know one fucking thing for sure.
我们挂了两个人 我们都不知道是怎么回事
Two of our people chalked  and we ain't got shit to show for it.
不 警察肯定会刨根问底的
Man, police gonna be real heavy on this, man.
我建议咱们别着急 先多找些人再说
I say we slow down take our time  to build our muscle...
扯 我哪有那么多时间
No, I ain't got  no more motherfucking time, man!
要是等那叫Marlo小子放话出来 说我被他搞了
When the word come out this boy,  Marlo, punking me,
我还混个屁啊
what I'm gonna look like?
我他妈还不如自己干了
I'm gonna go do this shit my damn self.
不不 你才回来
No, man, you just this minute got home.
你已经身上有命案 他们会撤回假释的
Your name come up in a murder beef, man,  they gonna pull your parole.
这事交给我处理吧
Let me take care of this.
我们考虑着 就我跟Cutty
We was thinking, man, me and Cutty you  know what I'm saying,
我俩动手就行 这样不就不会出事了
we could hit at them ourselves, man.  That way there won't be no fuck-ups.
听着 这事就交给你们两位了
Look, you two niggas get on it, man.
好好干
And get it right.
看到我怎么管事了吗 嗯?
You see how shit have to be handled, man?
就该是这么玩的 就这样
The game is the fucking game. Period.
一贯的风格
Same as it ever was.
我 我也说不好 老兄
I don't know though, man. I mean...
我是说... 我也不知道
I mean...I don't know,
我才去找在Vincent大街的几个年轻人谈过
I was just down the way with one  of our young'uns on Vincent Street
他们在那有几间空房
where they got the, you know,  the empty houses over there.
而且他们也有人在那
And they got crews over there...
卖迷幻药和可卡因就跟卖糖似的
twirling dope and coke  like the shit was candy.
现在小孩都有卖柠檬水的摊子 这世道已经变了
Kids with a lemonade stand.  It's a different world down there.
那些条子也就袖手旁观 好像这种事情是...
Like the cops was just standing  around like that shit was...
合法的
legal.
我是说 每天都是如此
I mean...every day.
贩毒就跟做生意一样
Now, that shit was business.
你刚说什么? 什么?
What you saying, man? What's up?
没事
Nothing, man.
啥也没
Nothing at all.
线人告诉我们那是Stringer的人干的
Our CI tells us those are Stringer's people.
你不是让我们查死人么 现在查到了
You want us to be about bodies, now we are.
原以为那小孩Marlo是给Stringer卖命的 但可能并非如此
We had this kid, Marlo, working for Stringer  but that might be wrong.
他现在可能因为占地盘跟人开战
He might be going to war for those corners.
再说明白点
Let me be clear.
现在不要搞Stringer Bell
This is no longer about Stringer Bell...
Kintel Williamson或其它什么人 也不要
or Kintel fucking Williamson or any of them.
我的官衔是什么 Greggs探员?
What is my rank, Detective Greggs?
- 我的官职 - 警督 长官
- My rank!  - Lieutenant, sir.
我是什么官职 McNulty探员?
What is my rank, Detective McNulty?
如果你们要是记不清楚
If you can't remember that much,
那你们就继续调查毒品去吧
then you can go the hell back to narcotics.
什么地方收留你们 就卷铺盖走人吧
And you can go to whatever the hell  unit will still have you.
从我办公室滚出去
Now get the fuck out of my office.
你的消息说你会在这
Your message said you'd be here.
但是我还是觉得会是你的小喽啰出现在这里
Still, kind of thought it'd be one  of your minions showed up in the flesh.
你找了我的人的家人
You called on some of my people's people.
我只是在工作而已
I was just working.
干我该干的事
Doing what a man is supposed to do.
我知道你一直忙
Well, I know you been busy.
这话是你从几个被从西区赶出来的 小年轻那听到的
Caught some talk from them young men  you rousted over there on the West Side.
我在查警用枪丢失的案子
That was about a gun belonged to a police.
对 这我也听说了
Yeah, caught some talk about that, too.
我来这 是为了别的事情
This here, it's about something else.
有个叫Tosha的姑娘在枪战中被人爆了头
Girl by the name of Tosha who got her head  blown off in a firefight.
如果你不打算合作 那你干嘛来?
If you're not here to cooperate,  then why are you here?
那好 到时候我会从你那里扽个姑娘出来
Okay, I could just pull up  that other girl from your squad.
她才不会跟你说什么
She ain't gonna talk to you.
没人会跟你讲什么
Ain't nobody gonna talk to you.
我过来就是这意思
I just came here to make that clear, man.
无所谓
Ain't no thing.
反正我已经有一个目击证人了
'Cause I already got me an eyeball wit.
真的?
You do?
我不相信啊
I don't know about that.
老Bruiser基本上啥都看不见
Old Bruiser, he be blind behind  that fortified half the time.
你要想让他出来指认 可得费口舌了
Shit, you gonna have to dry him out  just to get him on the stand.
再说 他已经准备改口供了
Besides, he done had a change  of heart to that story.
那都是我听说的
That's what I heard anyway.
靠 不说了 这事儿也算是那种...
Shit, past that, y'all gonna have  to call this one of them...
你们警察最近常说的那种 "犯事儿的代价"的案子吧
cost-of-doing-business things y'all police  be talking about all the time.
明白我意思吗?
You feel me?
不纳税的那种
No taxpayers.
操 在你们看来
Shoot, the way y'all look on things,
这就没有什么受害人
ain't no victim to even speak on.
你放屁 没人受害?
Bullshit, boy. No victim?
我刚从Tosha家人那回来 还记得么?
I just came from Tosha's people, remember?
你不觉得这些命案最后都会水落石出么?
All this death, you don't think  that ripples out?
我说什么你是不是都听不懂啊
You don't even know what the fuck  I'm talking about.
我早你几年进的Edmondson
I was a few years ahead of you at Edmondson.
但你应该还记得那环境曾经如何
But I know you remember  the neighborhood, how it was.
那有几个十足的混球
We had some bad boys for real.
那时候跟枪没啥关系
Wasn't about guns...
最多也就是赤手空拳玩玩
so much as knowing  what to do with your hands.
那些人真够混的
Those boys could really rag.
我父亲
My father...
对我严加管教
had me on the straight.
但跟其它年轻人一样 我也想混帮派
But, like any young man,  I wanted to be hard, too.
所以我就跟那群混人聚到一起了
So I'd turn up at all the house parties  where the tough boys hung.
见鬼 他们知道我不是他们那一类人
Shit, they knew I wasn't one of them.
几个混人过来跟我说
Them hard cases would come up to me and say
"小子 回家去吧 你不属于这里"
"Go home, schoolboy,  you don't belong here."
我都没意识到 那个时候 他们其实是帮了我
Didn't realize at the time  what they were doing for me.
就算周围再乱
As rough as that neighborhood could be...
我们也有自己的社区
we had us a community.
没人丢命 相安无事
Nobody, no victim, who didn't matter.
而现在这到处都是尸体
And now all we got is bodies...
还出了像你这样的畜生
and predatory motherfuckers like you.
而就在那姑娘丧命的地方 我看那群孩子都学着Omar的狠劲儿
And, out where that girl fell,  I saw kids acting like Omar.
喊着你的名字 要以你为荣
Calling you by name. Glorifying your ass.
妈的 真让我恶心 我们都堕落到这种地步了
Makes me sick, motherfucker,  how far we done fell.
2万5 这就足够搞定的
$25,000. You don't need more than  that to get it done.
你刚他妈说啥?
The fuck you say?
我刚跟你说了他们得如何搞定审批
I'm just telling you how they do down  at zoning and permits.
他们知道你已经签了大包
They know you got a general contractor...
而且他的人却坐视不管
and his people out there sitting on they ass.
他们也知道 多等一周 你就会多付他们一倍的钱
They know you paying twice  that every week they sit.
要2万5才能拿到许可?
$25,000 gets me the permits?
那2万是给你拿许可用的
$20,000 gets you the permits.
另外5千是我拿去贿赂城里那群废人用的
$5,000 is for me for bribing  these downtown motherfuckers.
我说 把钱塞到那群贼人手里的是我
I mean, I'm the one got to risk walking up
是我在铤而走险 没错吧?
to these thieving bitches  with cash in hand, right?
告诉你 String
I'm telling you, String...
现在那些掌管城市运行的人
the people running the city nowadays...
他们看着挺像那么回事
they make the last bunch look sanctified.
那些全是扯淡
I mean, this some shameful shit.
许可什么时候下来?
Permits come when?
最迟周一
Monday. Latest.
Cut 就是他
Cut, that's him.
白痴
Fool.
- 嘿 我认识那厮 老兄 - 真的?
- Yo, I know that nigga, man.  - Yeah?
- 还欠着我钱呢 - 是不是啊?
- Owe me money, actually.  - Yeah?
她可不是这么说的
She ain't say it like that.
不 她说还想要怀上什么的
No, she say it like she wanna  get pregnant and shit.
等等 你没事吧?
Hold on. You all right?
见鬼
Damn!
我枪开早了 老兄 堵了你的机会了
I opened up too early, man.  I stepped on your shot.
走 闪人
Come on, let's roll.
嘿 那来了几个条子
Hey, yo, there go five-o right there, yo.
我知道 没事
Yeah, I know. It's nothing.
嗯?
Huh?
条子让我们贩毒来着
The cops be letting niggas grind down here.
全都是...  赶紧滚 你们这群小矬子
It's all... Get the fuck out of here,  little hoppers.
滚一边去 小子
Get the fuck out of here, son.
这群小东西是干嘛的?
Who are these little niggas?
嘿 要是他们把我们抓起来怎么办?
Hey, yo, what if they lock us up?
希望你们都带牙刷了
I hope y'all got toothbrushes.
这里可不是什么男孩村 知道么
'Cause down in Boys' Village  you know what I'm saying,
如果你要没牙刷 就要用别人的
if you don't have no toothbrush you gonna  be using some other boy's brush...
要么就用手指搓吧
or rubbing your teeth with your damn finger.
如果不被抓
If you don't get locked up...
你们每人可以再多拿20块
y'all can keep an extra $20 each  off the pack.
干吧
All right.
谁有大麻?
Who got that fire, baby?
- 这有 - WMD!
That fire.
拜托 Tommy 放弃吧
Come on, Tommy, give it up already.
听我说 Terri 这次你得帮我
Look, Terri, you gotta do this for me.
说说你为什么想做市长
Tell me why you wanna be mayor.
还有我为什么要支持你 而不是Royce?
And why should I vote for you over Royce?
因为这座城市有问题 而我能改善
'Cause something is wrong in that city  and I think I can fix it.
你说的这人根本不屑于处理这些问题
This guy, he don't give a shit  about tackling the problems.
根本没人治理犯罪
Crime is out of fucking control.
就上周 一个小孩目击毒贩枪战 结果就送命了
Last week, a kid witness in a drug case  turns up shot dead
原因就在于管理漏洞
because of flaws in the system.
我去跟市长谈及此事 他说过他会处理
I go to the Mayor who promises action.
然后这位鼓吹改革超出能力范围的市长
And then Mr. "Reform is more  than the watchword of my administration"...
然后拍拍我的屁股 感谢我的关注
pats me on the ass,  thanks me for my concern...
告诉我门在哪里 就完了
points me out the door. The end.
那 用犯罪这招棋
So, with crime
就能在这座一多半是黑人的城市 推掉现任黑人市长
as the issue the great white father  rides to the rescue...
以一个白人父母官的身份扮演拯救者的角色了?
against a black incumbent mayor,  in a city that's 65% black?
黑人 白人 新手 人民很生气
Black, white, green, people are pissed off.
你觉得这可行么?
What makes you think this is doable?
首先  我听说市长跟他最关键的支持者出了问题
One, I hear the Mayor's got problems  in his base and with key supporters.
其次 警察专员 Royce钦点的人
Two, I got the Police Commissioner Royce's  own man,
告诉我他那个部门一事无成
telling me all kinds of stuff  about his fucked-up department...
告诉我Royce圈内的事情
and about Royce's inner circle.
再次 第5区的那个Tony Gray
And three, Tony Gray,  from the Fifth District...
走过来跟我说 他考虑竞选市长
comes pretty close to telling me  he's thinking about a run for mayor.
那就足以分散黑人的选票
That'd split the black vote.
你还缺个人
You'd still need a player
能把黑人中产阶级的票拉给白人
who gives the black middle class permission  to vote against one of their own.
你有合适人选么?
You got one of those in your pocket?
基本没有
Not many of those around.
Elijah?
黑人同盟才不会给你的小白屁股保底
Congressional Black Caucus ain't gonna  save your skinny white ass.
Odell Watkins如何?
What about Odell Watkins?
你能提到他倒是有点意思
Well, it's funny you should mention him...
我想他肯定现在非常不爽这个市长
'cause I don't think he's too happy  with the Mayor right now.
我不知道 只听说Royce在最近一次民调中 反对的声音很高
I don't know. I hear a new poll shows  Royce's negatives pretty high.
那最好还是先多筹点钱吧
You'd have to raise a load of dough.
他肯定看了 我就知道
He has to see it. I know he sees it.
现在太迟了
It's past that now.
我们是该尊重他点
It's about us showing some respect.
尊重个屁
Oh, fuck respect.
- 他又不对 - 是不对
- He ain't right.  - No, he ain't.
但到了这份上 你还是跟他观点不同
But at this point, with you on  the other side of the argument,
他肯定会坚持错误
he'd rather be wrong.
或许这话从他上级嘴里说出来
Maybe if the word came down from on high...
就能让他转念
it might change his mind.
我是说
I mean...
如果朋友Bunny Colvin 那么热衷于凶杀案
if your friend Bunny Colvin's up  to his ass in bodies.
我打赌他会愿意接受一切帮助
I bet he'd take all the help he can get.
我不是说你之前背着别人干过这种事情啊
Not that you'd ever go behind  anybody's back or anything like that.
是吧?
Right?
绝不可能
No way.
昨天有两个人被杀
Two more murders yesterday.
今天又有三人...
Another three today...
还包括一个14岁的
including a 14-year-old.
我们已经尽力了
We're doing all we can.
今年已经有260个人了
You're at 260 for the year...
现在才刚到10月
and it's barely October.
你跟我承诺的可是不到275个 Erv
You promised me 275 or under, Erv.
那话我可是当作诺言
I had that as a promise.
- 先生 - 要是年前到了300人
Sir... We see 300 before the New Year...
我也不敢保证你能不能干完任期
and I'm not sure that I can  justify a full term for you.
我不想这么说 但情况就是如此
Now, I hate to say it, but there it is.
是Barksdale的人跟谁?
Barksdale's people and who?
Marlo Stanfield
Marlo Stanfield.
是新来的小孩
It's the new kid.
我们已经盯了他几周
We've been on him a couple weeks.
我以为Daniels的人都在西北混
I thought Daniels' people are up  in the Northwest.
警长 你这边情况会越来越糟
Look, your war's only gonna get worse, Major.
西北那边已经消停几周了
Northwest has been quiet for weeks.
你甘愿在警督背后搞小动作么
You willing to backdoor  your lieutenant like this, huh?
你一点都没变 Jimmy
You ain't changed, Jimmy.
见鬼
Shit.
为了查案 你什么都不顾了 对吧
It's always about your case, huh?
你就尽力而为吧
Do what you can.
别把我供出来啊
Keep my name out of it.
办得如何?
How'd it go?
我们干掉了那俩人中的一个
We got one of the two of them motherfuckers,  you know?
你们晃悠来这
You mean, you motherfuckers  come strolling in here
- 还理直气壮的跟我说这 - 我说B
- all walking tall and shit... - Yo, B, man, I'm saying, man...
我们当时抽高了 知道吗?
we was blazing on them dudes. Man,  you know what I'm saying?
还high着呢 正爽的时候
Just got in the heat, man.  We was blazing, though.
- 就像是... - 得 得 放松点
- It was like...  - All right, all right. Relax, man.
我已经听说了 坐下吧
I already heard. Go sit down.
我不想计较什么
I'm not tweaking behind none of this.
又少一个混蛋能活到明天
That's one less motherfucker  that's breathing than was yesterday.
明白我说的么 这很好
You know what I'm saying? So we all good.
但我还是觉得很意外
But I'm surprised at you, though, man.
之前你不会失手的啊
Shit didn't get by you back when.
不是他的错
Wasn't my man's fault, man.
我朝那小的开枪太早了
I unloaded on the young'un too soon, man.
给他时间溜走了
Gave him enough room to buck and run, man.
这事是我自己搞砸的 知道吗
I fucked that shit up myself, you know.
等等
Hold on.
这事不怪他
It's on me.
我已经看到那小子了
I had that kid in my sights...
近到足够把他脑袋连同帽子一起轰掉的
close enough to take off his Kangol  and half his dome with it.
就是扣不了扳机
Couldn't squeeze the trigger.
我下不了手 老兄
Couldn't do it, man.
为什么?
Why not?
我没那种魄力了
Wasn't in me, I guess.
我是说
You know,
就是那种
whatever it is in you...
让你可以如鱼得水的...
that lets you flow like you flowing...
做那种事情的魄力
do that thing.
我已经没有了
It ain't in me no more.
好吧
All right.
你做不成这种事情了 但你还没完
So you done soldiering,  but you ain't done.
我们还可以用你当参谋
Could use you for what you got in your head.
可以派你去街角去 你可以不出门...
We're gonna put you on a corner,  you could be inside...
不
No, man.
我没说清楚
I ain't making myself clear.
我再也干不下去了
The game ain't in me no more.
做什么都不行了
None of it.
但你别的什么都不会做啊
But you ain't done shit else.
明白么? 你打算干什么去?
You know what I'm saying?  So what you gonna do?
不知道
I don't know.
但肯定不像这样
But it can't be this.
那好吧 就这样吧
All right then. We straight.
- 再见 - 再见
- See you.  - See you.
B 之前他可是个真汉子啊 知道吗
B, he was a man in his time, you know?
是啊
Yeah.
他今天就是个汉子
He a man today.
是条汉子
He a man.
知道是什么事吗?
Any idea what this is about?
队长
Lieutenant
他在想什么
What's he got in his head, right?
人来了 Bunny
Here he is, Bunny.
Cedric Daniels来救火了
Cedric Daniels to the rescue.
焦点人物啊
Man of the hour.